<!--
         The main elements in this document correspond to sections of text in the
         FOAF-a-Matic, e.g. the introduction. These sections can include any HTML
         markup.

         For the field, button, and message elements, please just translate the
         provided text: no markup is allowed in these elements.

         Note: for the missingFriendEmail message the ? symbol will be replaced by
         the name of the friend. Please incorporate that into the translated version as
         appropriate.

         Thanks!

         leigh@ldodds.com

    -->
<fm:translation lang="en" xmlns:fm="http://www.ldodds.com/ns/foaf-a-matic">
    <fm:languages>
    [<a href="foaf-a-matic.ja.html">Japanese</a>] [<a href="foaf-a-matic.fr.html">French</a>] [<a href="foaf-a-matic.es.html">Spanish</a>]
    </fm:languages>

    <fm:by-line>Describe yourself in RDF</fm:by-line>

    <fm:author>Written by <a href="mailto:leigh@ldodds.com">Leigh Dodds</a>.</fm:author>

    <!-- Add your name here, e.g. "Translated By <a href="">Your Name</a>." -->
    <fm:translator></fm:translator>

    <fm:introduction title="Introduction">
        <p>
        FOAF-a-matic is a simple Javascript application that allows you to create
        a FOAF ("Friend-of-A-Friend") description of yourself. You can read more about
        FOAF in Edd Dumbill's "<a href="http://www-106.ibm.com/developerworks/xml/library/x-foaf.html">XML
        Watch: Finding friends with XML and RDF</a>" article, at
        <a href="http://rdfweb.org/foaf/">the FOAF homepage on RDFWeb</a>, and also
        <a href="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/">the FOAF vocabulary description</a>.
        </p>

        <p>
        In short though, FOAF is a way to describe yourself -- your name, email address, and the people
        you're friends with -- using XML and RDF. This allows software to process these descriptions,
        perhaps as part of an automated search engine, to discover information about your and the
        communities of which you're a member. FOAF has the potential to drive many new interesting
        developments in online communities. Ben Hammersely's "<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/online/story/0,3605,870848,00.html">Click to the Clique</a>" article for the
        Guardian Unlimited website further explores these ideas.
        </p>

        <p>
        The FOAF-a-Matic is being provided as a quick and easy way for you to create your own
        FOAF description. Simply work through the forms on this page and complete whichever details
        you'd like to add to your description. As a minimum you'll need to supply your name and email
        address, and similarly for any friends you might add. It's worth adding a few friends to
        your description (but feel free to add as many as you like) because then when FOAF harvesters
        index your FOAF description, they'll be able to tie you all together as a network of individuals.
        </p>

        <p>
        Note: none of the information you enter in this page is used or stored in any way. The processing is entirely client-side,
        so your privacy is assured.
        </p>

        <p>
        If you have comments about this application, or further questions about FOAF, why not join <a href="http://rdfweb.org/mailman/listinfo/rdfweb-dev">the RDFWeb-dev mailing list</a>?
        </p>

        <p>
        <b>Update</b>: I'm currently writing the <a href="http://www.ldodds.com/wordtin/Wiki.jsp?page=FOAFaMaticMark2">FOAF-a-Matic Mark 2</a> a
        desktop application for creating and managing your FOAF data.
        </p>
    </fm:introduction>

    <fm:forms title="The Forms"/>

    <fm:personal title="Personal">
        <p>
        Some information about you, and how people can contact you.
        </p>
    </fm:personal>

    <fm:work title="Work">
        <p>
        Information about the place you work.
        </p>
    </fm:work>

    <fm:school title="School">
        <p>
        Where did you go to school?
        </p>
    </fm:school>

    <fm:friends title="People You Know">
        <p>
        Tell FOAF-a-matic about some people you know. Click "Add Friend" to add space to add more people. If
        you friend already has a FOAF description, then place a link to it in the 'seeAlso' field.
        </p>
    </fm:friends>

    <fm:results title="Generate Results">
        <p>
        Now you've filled in the details you're ready to be turned into FOAF...
        </p>
    </fm:results>

    <fm:what-next title="What Next?">
        <h3>Publish Your FOAF description</h3>

        <p>
        This is the easy part. Simple copy the generated FOAF description from the text box above and paste it into a file. Put the
        file onto your website somewhere where it's publically accessible, it's a good idea to name this file "foaf.rdf" as then a google
        search can be used to help discover FOAF files across the web.
        </p>

        <p>
        Your FOAF description is now ready, you just need people to come along and read it...
        </p>

        <h3>Joining the FOAF Community</h3>

        <p>
        The 'discovery' aspect of FOAF (i.e. how FOAF compliant applications find your description) is still an area under discussion. If you have
        suggestions then send them to <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/rdfweb-dev/">the RDFWeb-dev mailing list</a>. However there
        are three possibilities. You may want to try some or all of them.
        </p>

        <h4>Using the Link Tag</h4>

        <p>
        Aaron Swartz has <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/rdfweb-dev/message/190">suggested</a> using the HTML Link tag to point to FOAF descriptions, in a similar way that many bloggers
        are pointing to their RSS feeds. Here's how it should look:
        </p>

        <code>
        &lt;link rel="meta" type="application/rdf+xml" title="FOAF" href="foaf.rdf" />
        </code>

        <h4>Referrals from a Friend</h4>

        <p>
        The other recommended way to get your FOAF file indexed is to have someone else (i.e. a friend) point to it. A FOAF spider can
        then traverse all FOAF files. You can do this by making the following changes to your FOAF description:
        </p>

        <ol>
        <li>Alter the <code>rdf:RDF</code> element to add the RDF Schema namespace, as follows:
        <code>&lt;rdf:RDF
              xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
              xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
              xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#">
        </code>
        </li>
        <li>You can then add links to other FOAF descriptions by adding one <code>rdfs:seeAlso</code> element for each
        additional file, as follows:</li>
        <code>
        &lt;rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="http://www.example.com/friends.xrdf"/>
        &lt;rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="http://www.ldodds.com/webwho.xrdf"/>
        </code>
        </ol>

        <p>
        <i>Update</i>: if your friends already have a FOAF description, then include it in the 'seeAlso' field given in the form
        above. You can also <a href="http://www.ldodds.com/blog/archives/000033.html">Refer a Friend to the FOAF-a-matic</a>
        </p>

        <h4>Using the FOAF Bulletin Board</h4>

        <p>
        An obvious way for applications to discover FOAF descriptions is for there to be a registry of people. I've cooked up a
        simple way to do this called the <a href="bulletin-board.html">FOAF Bulletin Board</a>. Simply visit the FOAFWiki,
        and edit the <a href="http://rdfweb.org/rweb/wiki/wiki.pl?FOAFBulletinBoard">FOAFBulletinBoard</a> page and add your name and a link to your FOAF description. I've added mine already which
        you can use as an example.
        </p>

        <p>
        Applying the magic of HTML Tidy and XSLT means that applications such as Edd Dumbill's <a href="http://usefulinc.com/foaf/foafbot">FOAFbot</a>
        can process this index. Visit the FOAFBot home page for information about how to see it in action.
        </p>
    </fm:what-next>

    <fm:license title="License">
        <p>
        This work is licensed under a
        <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/1.0/">Creative Commons License</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
        <!-- Creative Commons License -->
        <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/1.0/"><img alt="Creative Commons License" border="0" src="http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights.gif" /></a><br />
        <!-- /Creative Commons License -->
        </p>
    </fm:license>

    <fm:fields>
        <fm:field id="friend" name="Friend"/>
        <fm:field id="title" name="Title (Mr, Mrs, Dr, etc)"/>
        <fm:field id="firstName" name="First Name"/>
        <fm:field id="surname" name="Last Name (Family/Given)"/>
        <fm:field id="nick" name="Nickname"/>
        <fm:field id="email" name="Your Email Address"/>
        <fm:field id="homepage" name="Homepage"/>
        <fm:field id="depiction" name="Your Picture"/>
        <fm:field id="phone" name="Phone Number"/>
        <fm:field id="workplaceHomepage" name="Work Homepage"/>
        <fm:field id="workInfoHomepage" name="Page describing what you do at work"/>
        <fm:field id="schoolHomepage" name="School Homepage"/>
        <fm:field id="spamProtect" name="Protect email addresses from spammers"/>
        <fm:field id="friendEmail" name="Email"/>
        <fm:field id="friendName" name="Name"/>
        <fm:field id="friendSeeAlso" name="See Also"/>
    </fm:fields>

    <fm:buttons>
        <fm:button id="addFriend" title="Add Friend"/>
        <fm:button id="generate" title="FOAF me!"/>
        <fm:button id="reset" title="Reset Form"/>
    </fm:buttons>

    <fm:messages>
        <fm:message id="missingRequired">You must complete these fields:</fm:message>
        <fm:message id="missingFriendEmail">An Email Address For ?</fm:message>
    </fm:messages>
</fm:translation>
